RG 062:042, Town of East Hampton
Connecticut State Library
Town of East Hampton records
1803-1976
Connecticut State Library
East Hampton (Conn.)
20.75 cubic feet
Administrative, election, school, land, and tax records for the town of East Hampton.
RG062_042
Multiple
Historical Note
The town of East Hampton was incorporated as Chatham in October 1767 and was taken from Middletown.
Scope and Content
Administrative, election, school, land, and tax records for the town of East Hampton.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- East Hampton -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- East Hampton -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- East Hampton -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- East Hampton -- Registers; Elections -- Connecticut -- East Hampton -- Statistics; Voting -- Connecticut -- East Hampton -- Statistics; Deeds -- Connecticut -- East Hampton; School enrollment -- Connecticut -- East Hampton -- Statistics; Schools -- Connecticut -- East Hampton -- History -- Sources
Places:
East Hampton (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
New Exemption: Public Act 11-242, section 37 amends subsection (b) (10) of Conn. Gen. Stat. sec. 1-210 and adds to the exemptions of the Freedom of Information Act any records created as a result of a doctor-patient or a therapist-patient relationship. This closure applies to the Daily Report Forms listed below as Restricted.
School Records: The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) of 1974 applies to all educational records including student records prior to the enactment of the law if the school or district was operating at or after enactment. This closure applies to the school registers after 1900 listed below as Restricted.
See the policy.
Provenance
The records in accession 2015-016 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library by the Town of East Hampton on October 21, 2014.
Container List
- Records, 1803-1930
  - T000344, 18.5 cubic feet
    - Tax abstracts
      There are separate tax abstracts for East Hampton, Chatham, and Middle Haddam.
      The 1842 Middle Haddam tax abstract includes a list of voters.
      Boxes 5, 6, and 21 are on oversize shelving.
      - 1820-1831 (Box 1)
      - 1831, 1832, 1833, 1834, 1835, 1836 (Box 2)
      - 1837, 1838, 1839, 1840, 1841, 1842, 1843 (Box 3)
      - 1844, 1845, 1846, 1847, 1848, 1849, 1850, 1851, 1852 (Box 4)
      - 1852, 1853, 1854, 1855, 1856, 1857, 1858, 1859 (Box 5)
      - 1860, 1861, 1862, 1863, 1864 (Box 6)
      - 1865, 1866, 1867, 1868, 1869 (Box 7)
      - 1870, 1871, 1872 (Box 8)
      - 1873, 1874, 1875, 1876, 1877 (Box 9)
      - 1878, 1879, 1880, 1881, 1882 (Box 10)
      - 1883, 1884, 1885, 1886 (Box 11)
      - 1887, 1888, 1889 (Box 12)
      - 1890, 1891, 1892, 1893, 1894 (Box 13)
      - 1895, 1896, 1897, 1898, 1899 (Box 14)
      - 1899, 1900, 1901 (Box 15)
      - 1902, 1903 (Box 16)
      - 1904, 1905, 1906 (Box 17)
      - 1907, 1908, 1909 (Box 18)
      - 1910, 1911, 1912 (Box 19)
      - 1913, 1914 (Box 20)
      - 1915, 1916, 1917 (Box 21)
      - 1918, 1919, 1920, 1921, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1925, 1926, 1927, 1928, 1929, 1930 (Box 22)
      - Unidentified and Undated (Box 23)
    - Rate books, 1849-1876 (Box 24)
    - Records probably kept by East Hampton Town Clerk and Treasurer, Zebulon Penfield, 1806-1835 (Box 24)
    - Include town meeting minutes and warnings, certificates of electors, election returns, treasurer's records, grand list reports, tax warrants and abatements, cattle and liquor licenses, military records, highway records, legal records, school district meeting minutes, and correspondence and financial records of the Penfield family, 1805-1849 (Box 24)
    - Deeds, bills of sale, 1803-1839 (Box 25-26)
  - 2015-016, 2.25 cubic feet
    - School Records, 1878-1937
      - Center District registers, 1878-1889 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
      - Chestnut Hill District registers, 1878-1889 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Clark's Hill District registers, 1878-1888 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Clark's Hill District East District registers, 1888-1889 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - East Hampton District registers, 1878-1890 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
      - Gate District registers, 1878-1889 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Middle Haddam District registers, 1878-1890 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
      - North District and Northwest District registers, 1878-1890 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
      - North Center District registers, 1878-1890 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Pine Brook District registers, 1878-1890 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - South East District registers, 1878-1890 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Connecticut School Registers - blank registers, 1885-1886 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Connecticut School Registers - covers, circa 1881, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - District Committee reports, 1880-1885, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - District Nurse Association of Middletown, Inc. Records, 1959-1976
      - Assembly of Home Health Agencies National League for Nursing resolutions, circa 1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - The Association of Community Health Service Agencies by-laws, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Budgets, 1971, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Clinic for Audio-Vision Screening - statistics, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Personnel Policies of the District Nurse Association of Middletown, Inc., 1970 September (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Physical Examinations and Immunizations Administered at Well Child Conference - statistics, 1968-1969, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Public Health Nursing Report - School Health Services, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Report of Child Clinic Health Activities, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Report of Public Health Nursing Services, 1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Reports - monthly and annual, 1959-1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
      - Salaries, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - School Health supply requests, 1965 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Restricted
      - Daily Report Forms, 1965 May-June; 1 folder (Box 3)
        Forms contain patient names.
      - School registers, 1925-1927, 1930-1937; 9 volumes (Box 3)
        Registers consist of the following schools: Center, East Hampton, Gate, Hurd Park, Middle Haddam, Northwest, and White Birch.